[
    {
        "question": "1. What commodity is associated with OPEC?", 
        "optionA": "Coffee", 
        "optionB": "Iron and Steel", 
        "optionC": "Vegetable oil",
        "optionD": "Mineral oil",
        "answer": "Mineral oil"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Which of the following countries has the least potential for the production of steel?", 
        "optionA": "India", 
        "optionB": "Cuba", 
        "optionC": "Japan",
        "optionD": "Germany",
        "answer": "Cuba" 
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Lake Kivu and Malawi are related in that they_________",
        "optionA": "Lie in the Northern Hemisphere",
        "optionB": "crater lakes",
        "optionC": "Attract a large number of tourists",
        "optionD": "the shoot was respiring and lost weight at rate of 1g per hour",
        "answer": "Are rift valley lakes"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. The oldest system of agriculture in Nigeria which now survives only in very remote areas is",
        "optionA": "Crop rotation",
        "optionB": "Mixed farming",
        "optionC": "Shifting cultivation",
        "optionD": "Market gardening",
        "answer": "Shifting cultivation"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. British foreign investments are concentrated in",
        "optionA": "EU countries",
        "optionB": "Commonwealth countries",
        "optionC": "Developed countries",
        "optionD": "Asian countries",
        "answer": "Commonwealth countries"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. A type of land-form that is associated with large scale orogeny is a",
        "optionA": "Fold mountain",
        "optionB": "Residual mountain",
        "optionC": "Block mountain",
        "optionD": "Volcanic mountain",
        "answer": "Fold mountain"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. The plains formed when the slopes of mountains are worn back in arid and semi-arid regions my mechanical weathering is called_______",
        "optionA": "Alluvial plains",
        "optionB": "Outwash plains",
        "optionC": "Pediplains",
        "optionD": "Savanna plains",
        "answer": "Pediplains"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. One of the following is associated with wind deflation in arid region_________",
        "optionA": "Barchan",
        "optionB": "Yardang",
        "optionC": "Rock pedestals",
        "optionD": "Oasis",
        "answer": "Yardang"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. A feature commonly found in the youthful stage of a river is",
        "optionA": "Levee",
        "optionB": "Meander",
        "optionC": "Ox-bow lake",
        "optionD": "Interlocking spurs",
        "answer": "Interlocking spurs"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. The extent of coastal erosion depends on the",
        "optionA": "amount of fresh water supplied by tributaries",
        "optionB": "depth of ocean water",
        "optionC": "salinity of the ocean",
        "optionD": "nature of the waves",
        "answer": "amount of fresh water supplied by tributaries"
    }
]